在之前的讲座中，我们介绍了姿势和姿势的概念;一种描述方式
In the previous lecture we introduced the notion of pose and poses; a way of describing
一个坐标系相对于另一个坐标系的平移和方向。
both the translation and the orientation of one coordinate frame with respect to another.
我们使用的符号基于希腊字母ksi，我们用它来表示姿势
And the notation we used is based on the Greek letter ksi and we used that to represent pose
我们用字母B下标来表示我们正在谈论这个姿势
and we used the letter B the subscript to indicate that we're talking about the pose
坐标框架B和前导索引，在这种情况下为A，表示该
of the coordinate frame B and the leading index, in this case A, to indicate that the
姿势是关于坐标框架A.因此我们将此符号读作B相对于A的姿势。
pose is with respect to coordinate frame A. So we read this symbol as the pose of B with respect to A.
三维事物并没有太大的不同，我们再一次使用这个抽象的概念
Things are not much different in 3-dimensions, once again we use this abstract notion of
由希腊字母ksi代表的姿势，现在我们代表翻译和方向
pose represented by Greek letter ksi, and now we represent the translation and orientation
一个三维坐标系相对于另一个的三维坐标系。后来在这个讲座
of one three-dimensional coordinate frame with respect to another. Later in this lecture
我们将讨论ksi的具体实现，它实际上意味着什么
we’ll talk about concrete implementations of ksi, what it actually means in terms of
您可以计算的东西，但现在只需将其视为抽象符号。
things that you can compute with, but for now just consider that as an abstract symbol.
符号与二维情况相同，我们读取此符号
The notation is the same as it is for the 2-dimensional case and we read this symbol
这里是坐标系B相对于坐标系A的姿势
here as being the pose of coordinate frame B with respect to coordinate frame A. And
记住这个姿势有两个组成部分，一个平移组件;那就是距离
remembering that pose has got two components, a translational component; that's the distance
在框架A和框架B的起源与旋转部件之间;我该如何旋转
between the origins of frame A and frame B, and a rotational component; how do I rotate
坐标框架A使其轴与坐标框架B的轴平行。
coordinate frame A so that its axes are parallel to the axes of coordinate frame B.
在三维中，描述对象的方向并不那么简单。考虑一下
In 3-dimensions it is not as simple to describe the orientation of an object. Consider this
飞机。它可以通过多种方式移动。它可以向上和向下倾斜
airplane. There are a number of ways in which it can move. It can pitch up and down, it
可以向右滚动或者它可以向左滚动，它可以偏向右侧或向右侧偏航
can roll to the right or it can roll to the left, and it can yaw to the right or to the
剩下。因此，有许多参数可以描述这个物体在太空中的方向。
left. So there are number of parameters that describe the orientation of this body in space.
因此，我们将这种形式化的方式再次类似于我们为此做的
So the way that we are going to formalise this is again similar to what we did for the
二维情况，我们再次将坐标框架附加到飞机上。
2-dimensional case, and again we attach a coordinate frame to the aircraft.
这里的另一个坐标框架，一个蓝色的坐标框架，我将把它固定到飞机上
Another coordinate frame here, a blue one and I'm going to fix it to the aircraft with
x轴指向前方，这意味着y轴指向机翼和机翼
the x-axis pointing forward and that means that the y-axis points over the wing and the
z轴指向上方。所以现在谈到描述这架飞机的姿势时
z-axis points upward. So now when it comes to describing the pose of this aircraft it's
得到一个平移分量，这是该坐标原点的位置
got a translational component, that's the position of the origin of this coordinate
框架相对于该坐标系的原点，然后有方向
frame with respect to the origin of this coordinate frame, and then there is the orientation of
该坐标系相对于该坐标系。
this coordinate frame with respect to this coordinate frame.
正旋转的方向是重要的概念，并且是二维的
The direction of the positive rotation is an important concept, and in a 2-dimensional
案件轮换被定义为在这个方向上是积极的。如果我们考虑二维
case rotation was defined as being positive in this direction. If we consider a 2-dimensional
坐标框架，然后如果我们从屏幕上增长一个z轴，那就相当于
coordinate frame, then if we grow a z-axis out of the screen, that is the equivalent
右手三维坐标系。所以这个正角度约定在两个维度上
right handed 3-dimensional coordinate frame. So this positive angle convention in two dimensions
对应于围绕z轴的正向旋转，该正向旋转从屏幕进入我们。
corresponds to a positive rotation about the z-axis which is coming at us out of the screen.
当我们谈论围绕轴的旋转时，我们定义了正旋转的方向
When we are talking about rotations around axes we define the direction of positive rotation
再次使用右手规则。所以我用右手拿着我的拇指指向
again using a right hand rule. So I take my right hand and I point my thumb along the
轴-在这种情况下，它是z轴，我的手指和方向卷曲
axis - in this case it's the z-axis, and I curl my fingers around, and the direction
卷曲的方向，我的手指尖是正方向。所以这
of the curl, the direction of the tip of my fingers is the positive direction. So this
是围绕z轴的正旋转。类似地围绕x轴旋转-这个
is a positive rotation around the z-axis. Similarly a rotation around the x-axis - this
围绕x轴的正旋转，这是围绕y轴的正旋转。
a positive rotation around the x-axis and this is a positive rotation around the y-axis.
当我们先前看到二维坐标系时，我们也有一个规则
When we looked previously at the 2-dimensional coordinate frame we also had a rule for the
二维正旋转方向。这是我们的二维坐标系
direction of positive rotation in two dimensions. Here's our 2-dimensional coordinate frame
再次，这是我们的x和y轴位于顶部。所以我们定义为正向轮换
again, here is our x and y-axis lying on top. So what we defined as a positive rotation
对于二维坐标系实际上是围绕z轴的正旋转，如果
for a 2-dimensional coordinate frame is actually a positive rotation around the z-axis, if
你可以想象一个z轴在那里。在机器人技术中，与许多其他工程领域一样，
you could imagine a z-axis being there. In robotics, as in many other areas of engineering,
将坐标框架附加到对象上非常有用和重要。现在是
it's really useful and important to attach coordinate frames to objects. Now here is
在飞行中我们可以附加右手坐标系的直升机的例子;
an example of a helicopter in flight and where we can attach a right-handed coordinate frame;
x轴指向前方，y轴指向右侧，z轴指向正下方。一旦
x-axis pointing forward, a y-axis out to the right, and a z-axis going straight down. Once
我们有一个连接到车辆的坐标框架，然后我们可以描述它的方向
we have a coordinate frame attached to the vehicle, we can then describe its orientation
相对于另一个坐标系。我们也可以尊重其动议
with respect to another coordinate frame. We can also describe its motion with respect
到这个特定的坐标系。向前是在x方向，向下是在z方向
to this particular coordinate frame. Forward is in the x direction, down is in its z direction
等等。在工业臂式机器人的例子中，我们可能有三维
and so on. In the example of an industrial arm type robot, we might have a 3-dimensional
连接到机器人底座的坐标框，以指示它的相对位置
coordinate frame attached to the base of the robot to indicate where it is with respect
到工厂的世界坐标框架，我们将附加另一个3D坐标框架
to the world coordinate frame of the factory and we will attach another 3D coordinate frame
对于夹子，按照惯例，z轴指向手指的方向，
to the gripper, and by convention the z-axis points outward in the directions of the fingers,
它可能接近一个物体来描述拾取的方向。按照惯例，y轴
the direction that it might approach an object for describing a pick up. The y-axis by convention
是指尖之间的方向，然后我们在x轴上绘制，以便创建一个合适的
is the direction between the finger tips, then we draw in the x-axis so as to create a proper
右手三维坐标系。
right-handed 3-dimensional coordinate frame.
如果我们查看非常着名的工程项目的细节，如阿波罗农历
If we look into the details of very famous engineering projects like the Apollo Lunar
任务，我们会查看一些在线可用的文档，我们在这里
Missions, and we look at some of the documentations which are all available online and here we
可以看到Apollo命令模块的x，y和z轴。同样对于农历
can see the x, y and z axis for the Apollo command module. And similarly for the Lunar
模块文档显示x轴垂直向上，z轴向前
module the documentation shows that the x-axis is vertically upwards and the z axis is forward
在前门的方向。这是一张巨大的土星五号火箭的照片
in the direction of the front door. This is a picture of the massive Saturn V rocket which
让宇航员登上月球并返回，如果我们仔细查看文档，
got the astronauts to the moon and back, and again if we look at the documentation carefully,
我们可以清楚地看到火箭早期阶段的轴线。某些
we can see that the axes for the early stages of the rocket are clearly indicated. Some of the
坐标框架约定实际上是在火箭外面绘制的，并且
coordinate frame conventions are actually painted on the outside of the rocket, and
如果我们仔细观察这个黑色环在这里所谓的仪器模块，
if we look closely at this black ring up here what's called the instrumentation module,
在肉体中实际上是一个非常庞大的装置，我们可以清楚地看到这里是画的
which in the flesh is actually quite a massive device, we can see quite clearly here is painted
正z方向的方向和背面的方向我们可以看到方向
the direction of the positive z direction and the one at the back we can see the direction
其负y轴。该模块实际上是土星的惯性测量单元
of its negative y-axis. This module is effectively the inertial measurement unit for the Saturn
Vrocket，功能现在可能与您口袋里的手机相当。
V rocket, functionality now is probably equivalent to what you have in the phone in your pocket.